(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ときのそら 5th Anniversary Live
『宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ』
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live
"Universe and Spacetime Milky Way"
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
Thank you for Flower stands!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
注意事項
Precautions
Thank you for Flower stands!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
注意事項
Precautions
Thank you for Flower stands!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
注意事項
Precautions
Thank you for Flower stands!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
注意事項
Precautions
Thank you for Flower stands!
ときのそら 5th Anniversary Live
宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live
Cosmos and Spacetime Milky Way
Please wait a moment until the show begins.
・携帯電話等は、マナーモードに設定し、
音の出ないようにお願いいたします。
・本公演の録音・録画・撮影は禁止です。
・Please set your mobile devices to silent mode
and ensure they do not make any noise.
・Recording, filming, and photography are prohibited.
・応援グッズをご使用の際は、
他のお客様のご迷惑とならないよう配慮をお願いいたします。
・When using support goods, please be considerate
of other audience members.
・会場内ではマスクを必ずご着用ください。
・会話や発声、飲食はご遠慮ください。
・Please wear a mask at all times inside the venue.
・Please refrain from talking, cheering, or eating.
注意事項
録音・録画・撮影の禁止
SNS等へのアップロードの禁止
Precautions
Recording, filming, and photography are prohibited.
Uploading to SNS and other platforms is prohibited.
Thank you for Flower stands!
ここに一冊の絵本があります
Here is a single picture book.
とても古い絵本です
It is a very old picture book.
その本が描かれたのは
That book was written...
この星からずっとずっと離れた 銀河をゆく船の中
...long, long ago on a ship traveling through the galaxy far away from this planet.
永い時をかけて 星から星へと旅する船です
It is a ship that has traveled from star to star over a long period of time.
この本は 船に暮らす子供たちのために描かれました
This book was written for the children living on the ship.
くら～い ばしょを 女の子が歩いてる
A girl is walking through a dark place.
目の前には どこまでも続く白い道
Before her eyes is a white path that stretches on forever.
いつから歩いているか わからないけど 元気に歩く
She doesn't know how long she's been walking, but she walks energetically.
「この道は光っていてきれいだな」
"This path is shining and beautiful."
「それにとっても歩きやすい！」
"And it's so easy to walk on!"
女の子は歩くのが好きみたい
It seems the girl likes walking.
元気よく てくてく歩いていく
She walks along cheerfully, step by step.
「あっ 流れ星！」
"Oh, a shooting star!"
「わあ きれいなお星さま！」
"Wow, what a beautiful star!"
「熱くはないみたい さわってみよう」
"It doesn't seem hot. Let's try touching it."
「光っていてすきとおってるわ」
"It's shining and transparent."
「お星さまものぞいてみよう！」
"Let's take a look inside the star too!"
「わあ みたことない世界！」
"Wow, a world I've never seen before!"
女の子は降ってくる星を通して 色々な世界を覗きます
Through the falling stars, the girl peeks into various worlds.
この絵本はとても古いものです
This picture book is very old.
なので 最後のページがなくなってしまっています
So, the last page is missing.
船の中にいる大人も子供も考えました
The adults and children on the ship thought about it.
結末がわからないのは残念だけど
It's a shame we don't know the ending...
続きのお話を考えるのは 少し楽しいことでした
...but it was a little fun to think of the rest of the story.
この本のタイトルは……
The title of this book is...
ときのそら 5th Anniversary Live
宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ
Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live
Universe and Spacetime Milky Way
ココココイスル 私 輝く
Falling in-in-in-in-love, I am shining,
ほら キラキラキラ煌めいてる
Look, I'm sparkling, sparkling, sparkling.
トトト 太陽みたいに笑う
Laughing like the su-su-su-sun,
私の 目まぐるしい
My dizzying...
ラブストーリー！
...love story!
皆、お待たせ！
Everyone, sorry for the wait!
ときのそらです！
It's Tokino Sora!
盛り上がってくよ！
Let's get excited!
あーもう やっんなっちゃうわ
Ah, enough already, I'm fed up!
今度ばかりは許せないの
This time, I just can't forgive you.
その悪気な...
That malicious...
…混ざざったキミの笑顔が
...your smiles all mixed together
だいだいだいだいだいだい嫌いだったはずなのに
Even though I was supposed to hate, hate, hate you...
いつからか大好きになった
At some point, I fell in love with you.
今日のところは許してあげるわ
I'll forgive you for today.
だから ほら 早く キミから答え聞かせて
So come on, hurry up and let me hear your answer.
いつまでも待たせるの？
How long are you going to keep me waiting?
もう目を逸らさないで
Don't look away anymore.
コココ恋する私 輝く
L-l-l-loving me, I'm shining.
ほらね キラキラ煌めいてる
See, I'm sparkling.
太太太陽みたいに笑う
S-s-s-smiling like the sun.
その笑顔が大好きなんです
I love that smile.
コココ恋する私 輝く
L-l-l-loving me, I'm shining.
ほらね キラキラ煌めいてる
See, I'm sparkling.
太太太陽みたいに笑う
S-s-s-smiling like the sun.
私とキミの 目まぐるしい
Between you and me, dizzying...
ラブストーリー
...love story.
ずっと気になってた
I've been wondering all along,
キミにふさわしいのは誰？
Who is the right person for you?
案外私自身とかいいかな？
Maybe it's me, after all?
ぐるぐるぐる駆け巡る
Going round and round and round,
プラスマイナス思考回路
Plus-minus thought process.
今日のところはひと休みするわ
I'll take a break for today.
でもね 本音だよ
But you know, it's my true feeling,
二人で見てきた景色で
In the scenery we've seen together,
確信へと変わる
It turns into conviction.
もう手を離さないわ
I won't let go of your hand anymore.
コココ恋する私 変われる
L-l-l-loving me, I can change.
いつもキミキミキミを想うから
Because I'm always thinking of you, you, you.
だだだ大胆 無敵になれる
B-b-b-bold, I can be invincible.
どうしてかなんて言わせないで
Don't ask me why.
コココ恋する私 輝く
L-l-l-loving me, I'm shining.
ほらね キラキラ煌めいてる
See, I'm sparkling.
太太太陽みたいに笑う
S-s-s-smiling like the sun.
私とキミの 目まぐるしい
Between you and me, dizzying...
ラブストーリー
...love story.
みんな盛り上がってるー！？
Is everyone having a good time!?
今日は声出せないけど、
We can't cheer today,
クラップとペンライトで盛り上がってね！
but let's get hyped with claps and penlights!
ごめんね待たせたね！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
二人 翼はないけれど
We don't have wings, the two of us,
繋いだ両手で無敵なの
but with our hands joined, we're invincible.
疑う余地もないわ
There's no room for doubt.
期待してて
Look forward to it.
コココ恋する私とときめく
L-l-l-loving me and fluttering,
ずっとキミキミキミと探してく
Always searching with you, you, you.
だだだ大好き そんな気持ちを
L-l-l-love you, that feeling,
10年 100年 いつまででも
10 years, 100 years, forever.
ココココココココ恋する
L-l-l-l-l-l-l-l-loving,
私輝く ほらね キラキラ煌めいてる
I'm shining, see, I'm sparkling.
太太太陽みたいに笑う
S-s-s-smiling like the sun.
私とキミの 目まぐるしく
Between you and me, dizzyingly,
いつでもぐるぐる忙しい
Always round and round, busy...
ラブストーリー
...love story.
胸に詰め込んだ
Stuffed into my chest,
夢はぐちゃぐちゃで
Dreams are a mess,
勇気がいるけど
And it takes courage,
キミにだけは見せようかな
But maybe I'll show them only to you.
一緒に行けるかな
Can we go together?
キミのバトンを
Your baton,
渡してこう
Pass it on.
深呼吸
Deep breath,
してみて分かったこと
And I realized something,
壮大で
Grand and...
笑っちゃうくらい好きだ
...it's so big I'm almost laughing, I love it.
最高さ
It's the best.
今うまく行かないことだって
Even things that aren't going well right now,
超えれる
I can overcome them.
僕の教科書
In my textbook,
いつに閉じたら
Whenever I close it,
何だってやれそうだ
I feel like I can do anything.
落書きの中光ってた
The feelings that were shining in the scribbles,
想いを
I'll...
キミとこうして交わし合えたなんて
...exchange them with you like this,
嘘みたいだなぁ
It's like a dream.
もっと
Keep on...
笑ってて、信じて
...smiling and believing.
未知の展開も
Unknown developments,
悪くはないよね
Aren't so bad, right?
酸いも甘いも
Sour and sweet,
集めたの
I've collected them.
味はどうかな
I wonder how it tastes.
成長できるかな
I wonder if I can grow.
共に見つめ合おう
Let's look at each other together.
歌おう
Let's sing...
上手く踊れなくたって
...even if I can't dance well.
最高さ
It's the best.
...考えて
...think about it
単純だら迷路
Simply a maze
楽しかった君ほら　一瞬で向こう
Look, you were having fun, and in an instant, you're over there
昨日よりも加速してる
Accelerating more than yesterday
ちょっと繋いでて
Just stay connected
簡単じゃないホームの掛け声は
The cheers from the platform aren't easy
いつも君が明るく放って支えてくれる
You're always there, brightly shining and supporting me
ずっと刻まれていくよ
It'll be etched in forever
みんな今日、見に来てくれてありがとー！
Everyone, thank you for coming to see me today!
2階席！
Second floor!
コメント！
Comments!
上手くいかない今日なんて　即興で歌
On days that don't go well, I'll improvise a song
明日の教科書見ずに閉じたら　何だってやれそうだ
If I close tomorrow's textbook without looking, I feel like I can do anything
落書きの中光ってた想いを
The feelings that were shining in the doodles
君とこうして交わせたなんて　嘘みたいだろ
Exchanging them with you like this, it seems like a lie, right?
もっと瞬きで記して
Mark it with more blinks
はい、というわけで、最初から『ぐるぐる・ラブストーリー』、『ロゴマジ』とお届けしてきました。
Yes, and with that, we've delivered 'Guruguru Love Story' and 'Logo Magic' from the start.
改めまして、ときのそらです！
Once again, I'm Tokino Sora!
みんな見に来てくれてありがとー！
Everyone, thank you for coming to see me!
うわー、もう人がいっぱいいる。当たり前なんだけど。コメントも見えてるよ、ありがとう。
Wow, there are so many people. Of course there are, though. I can see the comments too, thank you.
じゃあ、あれやろっか。2階席の人！
Now, shall we do that? Everyone on the second floor!
わー、ありがとう！
Wow, thank you!
1階席のみんな！
Everyone on the first floor!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
コメント！
Comments!
ありがとう！イエーイ、ありがとう。
Thank you! Yay, thank you.
本日は『ときのそら 5th Anniversary Live 宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ』昼公演にお越しいただきありがとうございます。
Thank you all for coming to the afternoon performance of 'Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live: Milky Way of Space and Spacetime' today.
今日はね、今年1月に開催したシアトリカルカバーライブ『Role Play』に続いて、昼と夜の2公演をやっていこうと思ってます。
Today, following the 'Role Play' theatrical cover live held this January, I'm planning to do two performances, afternoon and evening.
もうね、知ってる人は知ってる、知らない人は知らないと思うんですけど、私、ときのそらは今年5周年を迎えて…
Well, those who know, know, and those who don't, don't, but I, Tokino Sora, have reached my 5th anniversary this year...
ああ、ありがとう、ありがとう。見えてるよ、パチパチ見えてるよ。
Ah, thank you, thank you. I can see you, I see the clapping.
ペンライトも振ってくれてありがとう。持ってない人もパチパチありがとうございます。
Thank you for waving your penlights. And for those without them, thank you for the clapping.
なんかもう5年経ったんだっていう、すごい不思議な感覚があるんですけども。
It feels like a really strange sensation that five years have already passed.
それで、5周年に相応しいようにすごい頑張ってきました。
And so, I've worked really hard to make it worthy of a 5th anniversary.
スペシャルで、とても何か輝かしいというか、ミラクルなライブになっていると思うので…
I think it's becoming a special, very brilliant, miraculous live performance...
最後までね、目をパッパッと開いて、全力で楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you could keep your eyes wide open and enjoy it to the fullest until the end.
わーい！イエーイ！
Yay! Yay!
右の人！
People on the right!
左の人！
People on the left!
今日はね、今生の楽器聞こえてると思うんですけど、こんな素敵な演奏をしてくださる皆さんとも一緒に楽しんでいきたいなと思ってるんですよ。
Today, you can probably hear live instruments now, and I want to enjoy this with all the people who are giving such wonderful performances.
バンドの皆さん！今日はね、そらバンドがいるんですよね。
Everyone in the band! Today, the Sora Band is here, right?
そしてこれからね、ホーンの人とかストリングスの皆さんも出てきてくださいますのでお楽しみに。
And later on, people from the horn section and strings will also be coming out, so please look forward to it.
よろしくお願いします。よろしくお願いします。
Thank you for having us. Thank you.
みんな、2曲…まだ2曲だけど盛り上がれてる？
Everyone, two songs... it's only been two songs, but are you pumped?
盛り上がれてるね、ありがとう。ちゃんと見えてるよ。
You're pumped up, thank you. I can see you clearly.
うちわ持ってくれてる人、ぬいぐるみ持ってくれてる人、めちゃくちゃお洒落してくれてる人、ちゃんと見えてるよ。ありがとう。
The people holding fans, the people holding plushies, the people who've dressed up so stylishly, I can see you all. Thank you.
2階席のみんなももちろん見えてるからね。イエーイ！
And of course, I can see everyone on the second floor too. Yay!
そしてそして、もう一人…みんな楽しみにしてくれて…
And then, one more person... everyone has been looking forward to...
ねぇ？
Right?
すでに発表されてるんですけど、
It's already been announced, but...
今回のスペシャルなゲスト、
our special guest for this time...
いらっしゃいます！
is here!
会場のみんなには、心のね、中からは「うわーっ」て心で出して。
Everyone in the venue, please let out a silent 'Wow!' from the bottom of your hearts.
あの、声実際にだしたらちょっと大変なことになっちゃうから、あの、手と拍手で。
If you actually voiced it out, it would be a bit of a problem, so please use your hands and applause.
配信のみんなは、「イエーイ！」とか「うおー！」とか「やったー！」とか、
Those watching the stream, please say 'Yay!', 'Whoa!', or 'Hooray!'...
「あー！」でもいいよ。なんか、いろんなコメントで
...or even 'Ah!'. Please liven things up...
盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいと思います。
...with all sorts of comments.
さぁ、誰だと思いますか？
Now, who do you think it is?
コメントの人書けるかな？
Can the commenters write it down?
みんなで書いてみよう。
Let's all try writing it.
いくよ？
Ready?
せーの！
One, two!
広瀬香美さーーん！
Hirose Kohmi-saaaan!
そうなんですよ。今日はね、ゲストに大・大・大先輩の広瀬香美さんをお迎えして、
That's right. Today, we're welcoming the legendary Kohmi Hirose-san as our guest.
来てくれるなんて奇跡じゃない？すごいよね。
It's a miracle that she's here, isn't it? It's amazing.
ねえ。で、こんなふうにね、アーティストの大先輩の方とコラボさせていただくのって、
Right. And collaborating with such a prominent artist...
私初めてだと思うんだよね。
...is a first for me, I think.
自分のライブではもちろん初めてで、
Of course, it's the first time in my own live show.
前にもね、YouTubeにもお越しいただいたりしたんだけど、
She has visited my YouTube channel before,
もう緊張でガチガチで。
but I was so stiff with nervousness.
なんか、私がもしこうなってたら、みんな「うおー！」って
If I end up like that, I'd like you all to go 'Whoa!'...
「緊張しないで盛り上がれよ！」みたいな感じで、
...and 'Don't be nervous, liven up!'.
あの、そうね、やってくれたら嬉しいです。
Yeah, I'd be happy if you did that.
いやあ、しっかりとお届けできるように頑張りますね。
Well, I'll do my best to deliver a solid performance.
みんな、ついてきてくれるよね？
Everyone, you'll follow me, right?
ついてきてくれるよね？
You'll follow me, right?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
さてさて、おしゃべりしてばっかりなのもよくないでしょう、ライブですから。
Now then, it's not good to just keep chatting, after all, this is a concert.
というわけで、このあともがっつり楽しんでいきましょう。
So, let's keep having a blast.
それでは聞いてください。「空の空」。
Please listen to this. 'Karanosora'.
待ってです！
Wait!
あ、そうだ。ごめんなさい。あの、1個言い忘れちゃってました。
Oh, that's right. I'm sorry. I forgot to mention one thing.
なんと、YouTubeの無料配信はこのあとの曲の途中までということになっています。
Actually, the free YouTube stream will only go until the middle of the next song.
YouTubeで楽しんでいる皆様は、公式のサイトから続きも見れますので、
For those watching on YouTube, you can watch the rest on the official site.
ぜひ、せっかくここまで見てくれたから、このあともついてきてほしいななんて思います。
Since you've come this far, I really hope you'll stick with me after this.
緊張しちゃって、言いたいこと忘れちゃったよ。
I got so nervous I forgot what I wanted to say.
それでは、次の曲いきますかね。
Well then, shall we go to the next song?
今初めて聞いたみたいな反応して。
Act like you're hearing it for the first time now.
それでは聞いてください。「空の空」！
Please listen to this. 'Karanosora'!
昔いたことのある場所で　誤魔化せる傷ならもう癒えてる
At a place where I once was / If it's a wound I can deceive, it's already healed
ありったけ心まで　響かせる何かを探してる
I'm searching for something that resonates / To the depths of my heart
さあそばへ　群青と
Come close, with the ultramarine
境界を這う
Crawling along the border
空の空に落ちて
Falling into the empty sky
焦燥さえも　殻を割った僕を笑ってくれよ
Laugh at me for cracking my shell, even with impatience
暗い闇に落ちて
Falling into the dark shadows
ない未来に投げた響きに　何を置くの
What do you place in the resonance thrown into a non-existent future?
この信じられない僕を信じちゃいない
I don't believe in this unbelievable me
帰れる術なんて　最初から期待しない
I don't expect a way to return from the beginning
答えはないのが答えなのは　分かるだろうに
You should know that no answer is the answer
もっと求めて終わらせて
Seek more and bring it to an end
無料視聴パートはここまでとなります
The free preview part ends here.
全編ご視聴したい方は概要欄をご確認ください
If you would like to watch the full performance, please check the description box.
ときのそら 5th Anniversary Live
Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live
宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ
Milky Way of Space and Time
無料視聴パートはここまでとなります
The free viewing part ends here.
全編ご視聴したい方は概要欄をご確認ください
Please check the description for the full version.
無料視聴パートはここまでとなります
The free viewing part ends here.
全編ご視聴したい方は概要欄をご確認ください
If you would like to watch the whole thing, please check the description box.